Guide to the Helen Morris Hadley Papers, approximately 1880-1928
Archives and Special Collections Library, Vassar College Libraries
Helen Morris Hadley Papers
approximately 1880-1928
Hadley, Helen Morris, 1863-1939
0.4 cubic feet (2 boxes)
Archives and Special Collections Library, Vassar College Libraries
Bills and accounts from Hadley's days at Vassar and from subsequent reunions; and correspondence, speeches, and notes concerning her service at Vassar, approximately 1903-1927, including letters from Presidents Taylor and MacCracken; her Alumnae Association activities, 1913-1919; the Vassar budget, 1918-1928; and the controversy over dividing the Vassar History Department, 1906-1907.
Biographical Note
Helen Harrison Morris Hadley (VC 1883) was the daughter of Luzon B. Morris, governor of Connecticut from 1894-1896. She was born in 1863 and later attended Vassar College, graduating with the class of 1883. In 1904 she was elected an Alumnae Trustee and was a member of the board for three terms totaling seventeen years. Mrs. Hadley served on several committees, notably the Committee on Euthenics and the Executive Committee. She was married to Arthur Twining Hadley, a political economist who was president of Yale from 1899-1921. Their son, Morris, and his wife, Katharine Blodgett Hadley, also served as trustees of Vassar. Mrs. Hadley's sister, Mary Morris Pratt, was also deeply involved with the college; and her son, Richardson Pratt, was a trustee. Mrs. Hadley's interest was not confined to her alma mater; her service to Yale was recognized in 1935, when she was awarded the honorary degree of Master of Arts, and in 1959, a graduate women's dormitory was named for her. She died on 31 Mar 1939.
Scope and Content Note
Bills and accounts from Hadley's days at Vassar and from subsequent reunions; and correspondence, speeches, and notes concerning her service at Vassar, approximately 1903-1927, including letters from Presidents Taylor and MacCracken; her Alumnae Association activities, 1913-1919; the Vassar budget, 1918-1928; and the controversy over dividing the Vassar History Department, 1906-1907.
Access
This collection is open for research according to the
regulations of the Vassar College Archives and Special Collections Library
without any additional restrictions.
Subject Headings
Names:
MacCracken, H. N. (Henry Noble), 1880-1970; Taylor, James Monroe, 1848-1916
Organizations:
Vassar College--Alumni and alumnae; Vassar College. Board of Trustees; Vassar College. Department of History; Alumnae and Alumni of Vassar College (Organization); Vassar College--Students
Subjects:
Women--Education; Women's colleges--New York (State)--Poughkeepsie
VCL Categories
Vassar College Trustees
Encoding Information
Encoded by Elizabeth Clarke, August 2007.
Updated by Jason Kovari, March 2009.
Acquisition Information
Not known.
Container List
- Vassar. Includes statement about charter (Folder 1.1)
- Bills and accounts while a student at Vassar and for reunion activities (Folder 1.2)
- Letters from President Taylor, ca. 1905-1910 (Folder 1.3)
- Letters from President MacCracken, 1915-1927 (Folder 1.4)
- Other Vassar correspondence, ca. 1903-1920 (Folder 1.5)
- V.C. Board of Trustees (Folder 1.6)
- V.C. Board of Trustees - Committees (Folder 1.7)
- V.C. Budget, 1918-1928 (Folders 1.8)
- V.C. Budget, 1918-1928 (Folders 2.9)
- Alumnae Association of Vassar College, 1918-1919 (Folder 2.10)
- Provisional Alumnae Council, 1913-1917 (Folder 2.11)
- World War I activities at V.C. and in Connecticut (Folder 2.12)
- V.C. History Department - Controversy about dividing department, 1906-1907 (Folder 2.13)
- Association of Collegiate Alumnae (Folder 2.14)
- Speeches and notes (Folder 2.15)
- Non-Vassar correspondence (Folder 2.16)